wwf.ca 2016-11-24

# Privacy | WWF-Canada

Personal information is any information that can be used to distinguish, identify or contact a specific individual. This information can include an individual's name, contact information, social status and family relationships. Exceptions include business-related information and certain publicly available information such as business address, name, title and fax.

Personal information also does not include anonymous or non-personal information (i.e. information that cannot be associated with or tracked back to a specific individual).

**What personal information do we collect?**

We collect and maintain different types of personal information about individuals with whom we interact which is relevant to administer and manage a supporter-charity relationship.

This includes: 

  * Contact and identification information, such as your name, address, telephone number, mobile number, e-mail address and social media contacts;
  * Donation information such as date of gift, amount of gift, appeal (the campaign you contributed to), name of spouse or partner if it was a joint gift; receipt number.
  * Financial information such as your payment methods and preferences, billing and banking information (credit card number and expiry date or chequing account transit numbers, whichever payment type you prefer in order to process your donation);
  * Product and service related information concerning the sale of apparel, books and gifts and other products or services that we provide to you;

**  
Why do we collect personal information?**

WWF-Canada collects personal information to further its fundraising, public education and advocacy commitments, as well as to establish, maintain and manage our relationship with you. Certain information is collected to satisfy the requirements of Canada Revenue Agency (CRA).

**How do we use personal information?**

We will not, without your consent, use your personal information for any purpose other than as described in this privacy policy, except where permitted or required by applicable law or regulatory requirements. We use your personal information in order to administer and manage our relationship, to process donations, to respond to requests for information; to periodically keep you informed and up to date on WWF-Canada’s conservation activities, and provide you with opportunities to support our mission; to communicate to you special announcements or offers and opportunities to lend your voice or take action; and to invite you to participate in surveys or contests.

**Sharing of personal information**

Third party service providers may be engaged by WWF-Canada to perform a variety of functions, such as to mail our brochures, to process your donation, to fulfill your order or to provide technical services for our website, etc. These third party providers have access to personal information about you, if needed, to perform the functions for which they are retained. However, we direct that those companies may only use such personal information for the purpose of performing their roles and may not use it for any other purpose. In these cases, when information is shared, WWF-Canada requires reasonable assurance that the third parties will protect your information in conformity with our privacy practices. Some of these service providers may be located outside of Canada, in which case personal information shared with them will be subject to the laws of the country to which it is transferred. 

That country may have laws that require that personal information be disclosed to government bodies or courts under different circumstances than would WWF-Canada.

On occasion, WWF-Canada may exchange the names of some of our donors with other like-minded charities, unless you have asked us not to. Trading allows us to reach other Canadians who may be interested in supporting the work we do, to raise necessary funds, and to save substantially on fundraising costs. WWF-Canada trades names only after donors have had the opportunity to decline. WWF-Canada will not otherwise share or disclose your personal information except as may be permitted or required by law, or with your express consent.

For more information, please contact a WWF-Canada Donor Relations team member at **1-800-26-PANDA** , or write to us at WWF-Canada, Donor Relations, 410-245 Eglinton Avenue East, Toronto, ON, M4P 3J1, or email us at [CA-Donors@wwfcanada.org](mailto:CA-Donors@wwfcanada.org).

**Consent**

It is important to us that we only collect, use or disclose your personal information where we have your consent to do so. 

Typically, we seek your consent at the time that we collect the personal information. In certain circumstances, your consent may be obtained after collection but prior to its use or disclosure. If we plan to use or disclose your personal information for a purpose not previously identified, we will make reasonable efforts to advise you of this purpose before such use or disclosure. 

We may collect, use or disclose your personal information without your knowledge or consent where we are permitted or required to do so by applicable legal and regulatory requirements. 

Regularly, our donors are given opportunities to choose how often and in what way they wish to hear from us. At any time, our supporters are able to opt out of receiving communication material. Also, our supporters are able to opt out of having their information used or shared for purposes beyond those for which it was collected. To update your preferences, please contact a WWF-Canada Donor Relations team member at **1-800-26-PANDA** , or write to us at WWF-Canada, Donor Relations, 410-245 Eglinton Avenue East, Toronto, ON, M4P 3J1, or email us at [CA-Donors@wwfcanada.org](mailto:CA-Donors@wwfcanada.org).  
**  
Retention of personal information**  
We retain personal information about you for as long as is necessary to fulfill the purposes for which the information was collected and to comply with legal record retention requirements.

**Access to personal information**  
You can request to see the personal information that we hold about you. If you want to review, verify or correct your personal information, please contact our Privacy Officer using the contact information set out below. At that time, we will need specific information from you to enable us to search for, and provide you with, the personal information that we hold about you.

**Privacy practices**  
Personal information gathered by WWF-Canada is kept in strict confidence. Safeguards are in place to ensure that the information is not disclosed or shared more widely that is necessary to achieve the purpose for which it was gathered. Access is only given to employees who must use the personal information to perform their job function. Measures are in place to ensure the integrity and accuracy of the information and to prevent its being lost, stolen or prematurely destroyed.
